Jia Amanda Cooper

My mission is to develop software that has a meaningful impact on the way people live, interact with, and understand each other. I strive to use my skills to build bridges, close divides, and improve the lived experiences of people through technological advancement and intentionally created software.

Full Stack Developer Software Engineer Seattle-Based

Email: cooperama.8@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jia-amanda GitHub: github.com/cooperama

PROJECTS

Co[de]pendent (Dec 2020) TECH: React, MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, Node, bcrypt, JWT, SASS, FullCalendar JS library

REPO: https://github.com/cooperama/codependent

- The objective of this application was to create a scheduling platform for programmers to practice code challenges and prep for technical interviews.
- This project was conceptualized, designed, and implemented by me.

Flixr (Oct 2020) TECH: JavaScript, MongoDB/Mongoose, Express, Node, bcrypt, Bootstrap, OMDB web API

REPO: https://github.com/cooperama/flixr SITE: http://flixr-io.herokuapp.com/

- This web application serves to help the indecisive user find and select movies that match their mood and interests at the current moment.
- This project was collaboratively designed and developed by a team of two. The
 concept was based on my own personal indecision when it came to choosing a
 movie. As such, the implementation of the algorithm to determine the results
 brought back from the API was done by me. I also contributed to both front and
 back-end aspects of the application, including making API calls, performing CRUD
 operations, and creating user-facing web pages.

Wayfarer (Nov 2020) TECH: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, SASS

REPO: https://github.com/cooperama/Wayfarer

- Wayfarer is an online community where fellow travelers can see and discuss where they've been in a forum-style setting.
- Wayfarer was a project done in collaboration with three other developers using GitHub's Kanban for task management. I played an instrumental role in implementing back-end functionality, and contributed greatly to front-end layout and design.

Motchi-Gotchi (Sep 2020) TECH: JavaScript, HTML, CSS REPO: https://github.com/cooperama/motchi-gotchi

SITE: https://pages.git.generalassemb.ly/cooperama/project_0_tamagotchi/

- This is a simple web-based game modeled after the classic 90s Tamagotchi Pet game. Using DOM manipulation and vanilla JavaScript, the user can interact with the character, affecting the character's stats in order to keep it alive and happy.
- This was designed and developed independently as my first project in the GA's software engineering immersive course.

SKILLS

Languages & Markup
JavaScript | Python

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS Libraries & Frameworks

NodeJS | Express | React | Redux Django | jQuery | Bootstrap

Databases & Architecture

 $\label{eq:mongode} MongoDB/Mongoose \mid SQL \\ PostgreSQL \mid MVC \mid CRUD \mid REST \\$

Soft Skills

Effective communication Result-oriented work ethic Precise execution of tasks Adaptive to feedback Motivated learner Empathetic collaborator

EDUCATION

Michigan State University
May 2010
B.S. of Nutritional Sciences

TRAINING

General Assembly December 2020 Software Engineering Immersive

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

General Assembly Hackathon 2020

Best Overall Winner

Essentials

https://github.com/cooperama/essentials React, SASS, MongoDB/Mongoose

WORK EXPERIENCE

GATE School, Seoul, South Korea - ESL Teacher, Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

Instructed, led, and encouraged students in basic English starting at phonics, and building up to reading sight words, full sentences, and short stories, maintaining a compassionate and growth-mindset-oriented environment.

4D Content English, Montevideo, Uruguay - ESL Teacher, Jul 2017 – Feb 2019

Instructed professional adults in business English, utilizing relevant, authentic source materials in order to effectively demonstrate grammar and vocabulary as it is natively expressed.

Puruni Childcare Center, Seoul, South Korea - ESL Teacher, Mar 2015 – Feb 2016

Instructed and cared for children aged 4 -5. Designed and developed games and activities through which children could learn ABCs, vocabulary, and basic English phrases.